Guide to the Bob and Gennie DeWeese papers1946-2007
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- Bob DeWeese correspondence, 3; 5 boxes
  - Condolence Letters to Josh DeWeese - Regarding Death of Gennie DeWeese, 2007-2008 (Box 32, Folder 1-6)
  - Condolence Letters to Tina DeWeese - Regarding Death of Gennie DeWeese, 2007-2008 (Box 35, Folder 1-7)
  - Condolence Letters to Tina DeWeese - Regarding Death of Gennie DeWeese, 2007-2008 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Get Well Soon Cards to Bob DeWeese and Condolence Letters to Gennie DeWeese, 1989-1991 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Condolence Letters to Gennie DeWeese and Family - Regarding Death of Bob DeWeese, 1990-1991 (Box 37, Folder 4-6)
  - Condolence Letters to Gennie DeWeese and Family - Regarding Death of Bob DeWeese, 1990-1991 (Box 38, Folder 1-7)
  - Get Well Soon Cards to Bob DeWeese and Condolence Letters to Gennie DeWeese, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Condolence Letters to Gennie DeWeese and Family - Regarding Death of Bob DeWeese, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 2-6)
  - Letters to Bob DeWeese, 1961-1977 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Gennie DeWeese Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 40, Folder 2)
- Gennie DeWeese biographical files, 1948-2007; 4; 4 boxes
  This series contains personal effects, art materials, awards, newspaper clippings and gallery opening materials. Series 4 is divided into 2 subseries, personal and awards.
  - Personal, 1; 3 boxes
    This subseries contains documents about Gennie DeWeese's family history, as well as personal items she kept over the years.
    - Personalized Stamp (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Medal (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Ribbon (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Nametag (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "Gen" Wooden Square (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Sweet Pea Stamp (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - She May be Mom, but she's also a woman framed quote (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Family Memories, 1990-2006 (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
    - Family History - Genealogy, 2004 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Adams Family" - Gennie (Adams) DeWeese Family Research, 2005 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia, 1961-2000 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Claris Adams Memorial Service, The American Life Convention, "Mrs. Robert DeWeese", 1960 (Box 36, Volume 1)
    - Calendar, "In Praise of Women's Art" (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Calendar, 1988 December (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - MSU, 1984-1991 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Josh DeWeese Article, circa 2000 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Articles and Flyers - Gennie DeWeese Shows, 1966-2003 (Box 40, Folder 10-12)
    - Articles and Flyers - Gennie DeWeese Shows, 1973-2000 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
    - Gennie DeWeese Interview, Newspapers, Gallery, 1985-1995 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1993-2000 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Article in This Week, "Celebrating the life of Gennie DeWeese", 2008 June 20 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Awards, 2; 1 box
    Collection of awards given to Gennie DeWeese.
    - Artist of the Year honorary key, Yellowstone Art Museum President's Awards, (Gennie DeWeese), 2002 July 12 (Box 42)
    - MSU Honorary Doctorate of the Arts-with Commencement Documents, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
    - Senska-Wilber Montana Governor's Arts Award, 1985 May 18 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Montana Governor's Arts Award, 1980-1995 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Sign: "A woman has to do twice as much as a man to be considered half as good" (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Resume Statements (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - US Department of State Art, Certificate of Appreciation, Art in Embassies Program, 1995-2000 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Ageless Hero Award, Blue Cross and Blue Shield, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Gennie DeWeese working files, 5; 9 boxes
  Series 5 contains art projects, exhibition materials, notes, lists of artwork details, illustrations and newspaper clippings. The series is split into two subseries, projects and exhibitions.
  - Projects, 1; 4 boxes
    Examples of Gennie DeWeese's work such as sketches of murals, illustrations for projects such as Hamlet's Planets.
    - Miscellaneous Panels of the Arts Involvements, 1986-2005 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Montana Contemporary Art Marketing Study, 1994-1995 (Box 43, Folder 3-4)
    - Meetings - Suggestions, etc. (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Helen Schmidt Book, 1981-1982 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Gottlieb Foundation, 2005-2006 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Hamlet's Planets, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Gennie DeWeese Painting and Woodcut list (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Shows, museum correspondence, etc., 1975-2003 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Gallery and Exhibit Correspondence, 1982-2006 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Gallery Correspondence: San Francisco Gallery, Yellowstone Art Museum, Penelope Loucas Gallery, 1984-2002 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Morgan Gallery and Custer County Art Center, 1993-2007 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Toucan Gallery and UCross Foundation, 2000-2002 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Billings Clinic Hospital Mural, Corona Sexson, etc., 1979-2000 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Billings Clinic Hospital Mural - Photographs (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Scrolls": Art statements and pricing (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Hamlet's Planets sketches (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Hamlet's Planets manuscript (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Hamlet's Planets (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Women's Work Art Show and The Griffin Child illustrations, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Personal letters, art programs, newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Native American Art (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Fish, Wildlife and Parks Mural Proposal, 2002 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Lists, Prices (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Notebook (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "About Gennie," Terry Karson, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Mr. Somersets 4th Grade Visit to Art Museum of Missoula, circa 1996 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Gennie DeWeese Retrospective Art Museum of Missoula, 1992-2005 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Montana Artists Refuge, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Exhibitions, 2; 5 boxes
    Includes art lists and prices, notes and correspondence with galleries, gallery announcements displaying Gennie's works, as well as ones she may have been interested in.
    - National Endowment of the Arts, 1979-1990 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Women's Work: The Montana Women's Centennial Art Survey Exhibition, curated by Gennie DeWeese and Suzanne Katzanek, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Women's Work: The Montana Women's Centennial Art Survey Exhibition, curated by Gennie DeWeese and Suzanne Katzanek, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Notes and Remarks on Jessie Wilber Tipi Design Serigraphs (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Gallery Guestbook: Thank You Notes from Montana Art Gallery Directors Association (MAGDA), 1966-2003 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Contemporary Art Pamphlets, 1990-1993 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Spinsters Ink and R&F Handmade Paints info, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Women Who Make a Difference, 1986-2002 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Missoula Art Museum, Gennie DeWeese Retrospective, Exhibit layout sheets (mockup), 1990-2008 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Yellowstone Art Museum, 1979-2007 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Yellowstone Art Museum: Acquisition of Gen Paintings, 1995-2002 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Holtler Art Museum, 1997-2007 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Corona Vol. I, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Corona Vol. II, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - DeWeese Legacy, 1991-2011 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - DeWeese Legacy - Retrospective booklet, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - DeWeese Art Postcards, 1997-2004 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Gennie DeWeese Retrospective - Art Museum of Missoula, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Arizona State University: The Works of Gennie DeWeese, 1995-1996 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Invoices and Receipts, 1994-1996 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - "Gen" (speech text), 1996 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Notes and Letters to Gennie DeWeese, 1992-1996 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - "Your comments for Gennie DeWeese" - Comments from exhibition, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Art Museum of Missoula, Gennie DeWeese: A Retrospective, 1994-1997 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Gennie DeWeese Retrospective - Proofs, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Gennie DeWeese: A Retrospective, Resume, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 11)
- Gennie and Bob DeWeese Gallery, 6; 5 boxes
  Series 6 includes gallery materials, notes, guest books, publicity materials, newspaper clippings, press releases and correspondence.
  - Bob and Gennie Gallery - Price lists and sales books, 1987-1988 (Box 47, Folder 12-13)
  - At Home magazine, 2004-2008 (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Various Magazines and Art Auction Catalogs, 2011 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Various Magazines, 2005 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Art Auction Catalogs, 1988-2008 (Box 48, Folder 4-6)
  - Art Auction Catalogs, 1982-2003 (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
  - The Poindexter Collection, Yellowstone Art Museum, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Yellowstone Art Center, 1974-1989 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Yellowstone Art Museum Annual Art Auction, 2000-2007 (Box 49, Folder 5-6)
  - Paris Gibson Square Museum of Art Exhibition and Auction Catalogs, 1988-2002 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Art Magazines, 1992-2004 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Art Pamphlets, 1959-1998 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Missoula Museum of the Arts/Art Museum of Missoula Exhibitions, 1987-2004 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Peter Rutledge Koch, 1995-2000 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Montana State University Art Exhibitions, 1966-1974 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Women's Work: The Montana Women's Centennial, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Seattle Gallery Exhibitions, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Montana Cultural Treasures: Guide to Montana Art Galleries, Museums and Studies, 1997-1999 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Montana Artists, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - DeWeese Shows: Early Years, MSU, and Bozeman, 1949-1985 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - DeWeese Shows: Montana and Friends' Show Announcements, 1954-1993 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Northwest Printmakers, University of Washington, 1956-1961 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Seattle Art Museum Annual Exhibition of Northwest Artists, 1952-1961 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Gallery Paule Anglim and Loggia Gallery in San Francisco, 1958-1987 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Various Exhibitions in the United States and France, 1945-1990 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Retro Shows, etc., 1979-2006 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Ford Times, 1953-1956 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Bob DeWeese's Obituary, 1976-1993 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Artweek: Exhibitions: Joys of Process, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - DeWeese Contemporary Gallery, 1986-1987 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Artweek, 1987-1988 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Artweek and This Week magazines, 1984-1988 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Newspaper clippings, 1982-1987 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - DeWeese Gallery: Akio Takamori and Harold Schlotzhauer, 1986-1987 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - DeWeese Gallery Promotional Material, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Gallery Stuff, 1987-1988 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - DeWeese Contemporary Gallery: Miriam Sample, 1978-1987 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Gallery Announcements and Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases: Autio Trio (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - DeWeese Family Show: Prices and Inventories, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Stories, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - DeWeese Gallery Advertising, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - DeWeese Gallery Preview Show photos, 1985 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - DeWeese Gallery photos, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - DeWeese Gallery: Various shows: Josh DeWeese, Rob DeWeese, Gen DeWeese, Jerry Rankin, Clarice Dreyer show photos, 1985-1986 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Exhibitor Resumes and Statements, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - DeWeese Gallery Posters, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 2-3)
  - DeWeese Gallery Posters: Xeroxes (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Gallery Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 53, Folder 4-6)
  - Cash Book, 1985-1986 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - DeWeese Contemporary Gallery photos (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Inventory: DeWeese family artworks, 1980s (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Gallery Guestbook, 1985-1986 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - 'Gennie DeWeese 80th Birthday' (Box 55, Dvd 1)
    Tina DeWeese's compilation of Gennie's life in 444 photographs.
  - 'Thanksgiving 2007' (Box 55, Dvd 2)
    Tina DeWeese's compilation of photos of last DeWeese family gathering before Gennie's death.
  - 'At the DeWeese's' (Box 55, Compact-disc 1)
    Movie by Michael Sexton.
  - 'Bob DeWeese: A Look Ahead, Exhibition at the Holter Museum of Art' (Box 55, Dvd 3)
    By Martin Holt.
  - 'Bob DeWeese Panel, Holter Museum, Terry Karson/James Reineking/Markus Stangl/Wes Mills/Jerry Rankin, October 29, 2006', October 26, 2006 (Box 55, Compact-disc 2)
  - 'Terry Karson, Robert DeWeese "At Large" Leni Holliman YPR' (Box 55, Compact-disc 3)
  - 'DeWeese "House full of Art' (Box 55, Vhs 2)
    MSU Film and TV production by Bill Neff.
  - 'Tipi's Wessie' [Jessie Wilber] (Box 55, Vhs 3)
  - 'Montana Style: The Art of Bob DeWeese' (Box 55, Vhs 4)
  - 'Robert DeWeese Exhibition Tape, August 30, 1991' (Box 55, Vhs 5)
    Video of retrospective at Yellowstone Art Center.
  - 'Gennie DeWeese' (Box 55, Vhs 6)
    Compilation of photos of Gennie by Tina DeWeese.
  - DeWeese Gallery - Guest List (Box 36, Volume 2)
  - Slides and Photographs from the DeWeese Gallery (Box 36, Volume 3)
- DeWeese Web Archive, 2020; 7
  The DeWeese website was created and is maintained by Tina DeWeese to document and promote the DeWeeses' legacy. It includes photographs, written tributes, and other materials.